SUMMARY

With over ten years of experience designing software, I have developed expertise in a wide range of technologies and specialties. While my background in business intelligence has been a core focus, my skills extend to all areas of software development. I specialize in back-end development, but I am also capable of full-stack development and managing cloud-based infrastructure. With a strong understanding of the user experience and the technology stack that supports it, I am confident in my ability to help your company achieve its goals.

TECHNICAL KNOWLEDGE

- Microsoft C# (.NET 6/7 and Framework 4)
- Angular and C# Web API for web application development
- PHP, Python, Java, and other programming languages
- Microsoft SQL Server, including the business intelligence stack
- Cloud-based project development and management in AWS and Azure
- Data warehouse design using Kimball and Data Vault modelling

EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Developer

Apr 2022 – Jan 2023

Talen

- Design and build new bespoke web applications and develop bug fixes and new features for existing solutions based on customer requirements and proactive environmental monitoring.
- Develop custom microservices in Azure that can be leveraged by multiple client applications.
- Designed and deployed a complex custom authentication solution using Azure AD B2C.

Senior Business Intelligence Solution Developer

Apr 2012 - Nov 2021

Kinetic IT

- Developed bespoke .NET applications from websites to console data collectors that enabled much of the reporting and other business intelligence solutions.
- Developed data warehouses and reports that enabled our customers and engineers to better monitor their processes and ensured we met our contractual obligations.
- Worked with customers to determine their specific requirements and find the solutions that best fit their needs.

System Administrator

Apr 2006 – Jul 2008

RemedyOutfitters.com

- Coordinated and managed third-party service providers.
- Created custom tools and modifications for an open-source web-store using PHP and MySQL.
- eBay and PayPal automation using a custom inventory control system.

EDUCATION

AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner	Jan 2022
ITIL v4 Foundations	Feb 2021
Microsoft Certified Solutions Associate - SQL Server 2012/2014	Jun 2014
Microsoft Certified Professional	Jan 2005